Mark Seymour

Halifax, Nova Scotia(902) 497-8028

mark.seymour.ns@gmail.com
 markseymour.ca
 linkedin.com/in/markevanseymour

A web developer living in Halifax, Nova Scotia with over a decade of professional and personal experience in front-end and back-end development. A dedicated worker and team player capable of scoping out, planning, and developing advanced, attractive, user-friendly web solutions using modern web standards.

Highlights

- Photography
- Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign
- HTML5, CSS3, Sass, Less
- JavaScript, jQuery
- PHP, Laravel

- Joomla!, WordPress
- MySQL, Redis
- GIT
- Ruby

Work Experience

Web Developer Electric Playground

7/2014 - 8/2018 Bedford, Nova Scotia

- Displayed initiative in learning and suggesting new solutions and frameworks for client projects
- Engaged with clients along with CEO to learn project scope and present project updates
- Quickly built out client websites using a combination of Joomla! CMS and preexisting base templates using custom CSS and LESS, and customized modules to suit needs
- Efficiently maintained content of and upgraded client websites, including article management and rebuilding legacy themes for new CMS versions
- Planned and developed Laravel-based web applications including database design, custom
 Sass and JavaScript, and determined the scope of application features
- Collaborated with Creative Director to ensure a high standard of responsive web design

Graphic Designer (NSCC APPLIED PORTFOLIO)

MediaSpark, Inc.

4/2013 - 5/2013 Sydney, Nova Scotia

- Created icons and graphics for web browser-based gamified learning solutions, redesigned graphics for iOS-based games
- Photographed products for use in online promotional material
- Utilized Basecamp for organizing and completing tasks

Freelance Web Developer Bluenose Creative

2012 - 2014 Sydney, Nova Scotia

- Engaged with clients through complete service delivery, finalized projects and handover
- Supported clients through updating and maintaining websites when requested

Web Developer (NSCC APPLIED PORTFOLIO) Webbuilders Group

3/2010 - 5/2010

New Glasgow, Nova Scotia

- Made use of Photoshop and SilverStripe CMS to create dynamic websites for several properties
- Transformed static designs by the company's Creative Director into responsive web designs

Web Coordinator (VOLUNTEER) Maritimes Y's Men

2009 - Present

Halifax, Nova Scotia

- Maintained the regional website and responded to questions from regional members including club presidents and regional team
- Completed a total overhaul of the site November 2017 (http://maritimesysmen.com/)

Web Developer (VOLUNTEER) Cumberland Y Service Club

2007 - Present Halifax, Nova Scotia

 Developed a website for the Cross Border Challenge Race Series, operated by the club (http://crossborder.challenge.com/)

Education

Graphic Design

NSCC, Marconi Campus 2011 - 2013 Sydney, NS Applied Communication Arts & Tech.

NSCC, Marconi Campus 2010 - 2011 Sydney, NS ★ with Honours IT/Web Development NSCC Truro Campus 2007 - 2010 Truro, NS